wccnet.edu 2019-08-14

# 

Online Privacy Statement
PURPOSE
Washtenaw Community College (WCC) provides this website (“Site”) to
students, prospective students, faculty, staff, alumni and visitors of the WCC
electronic community for legitimate academic and administrative pursuits as
outlined by the College's mission statement.
WCC is committed to safeguarding the privacy of personal data in
compliance with federal and state laws, as well as WCC policy. This
privacy statement outlines the collection, use and disclosure of information
provided to the College through this Site and its other associated online
services available for students, applicants, employees and alumni.
CONSENT
Your use of this Site is subject to all applicable state and federal laws, as
well as general College policies. When you submit information to WCC, or
you use this Site and other services, you consent to the collection, use and
disclosure of that information as described in this Online Privacy Statement.
If you provide information directly to WCC from a location in one of
European Union (EU) member states or European Economic Area (EEA),
you consent to the transfer of your personal information outside the EU/EEA
to the United States.
The site may contain links to other Internet Web sites, including co-branded
or other affiliated sites that may or may not be owned or operated by
WCC. Unless otherwise explicitly stated, the College is not responsible for
the privacy practices or the content of such sites, including such sites’ use of
any information collected when visitors to the site click through links to
those sites.
                                                                               1

Please note that WCC periodically reviews these privacy practices, thus they
are subject to change. To contact WCC with questions or issues concerning
this online privacy statement or its application, please send email to WCC’s
Information Security Office at infosec@wccnet.edu or +1-734-477-8911.
WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?
This Site collects two types of information: (a) information that is collected
automatically when you visit this Site through cookies, third party tracking
technologies, and log data; and (b) information you voluntarily provide to
the College as a component of our services, which may include personal
information (such as your name, address, e-mail address, etc.).
Cookies
This website uses “Cookies” to help manage web site activity. A cookie is a
piece of data sent to your browser from a web site and stored locally on your
computer that is either maintained only for the duration of a particular
session visit or is stored on the user's computer to support future visits. See
Wikipedia’s Cookie page for more information.
This Site uses cookies for two main purposes: (a) to carry information about
your current session as you move from one web page to the next, which also
allows account holders to utilize single sign-on to automatically login to
other WCC websites; and (b) to identify you on return visits.
You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on
your browser. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may not be able
to use some portions of our Site.
Google Analytics
This Site uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by
Google, Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses cookies to analyze the
behavior of visitors to this Site and the information is collected for the
purpose of evaluating your use of the various parts of this Site, compiling
reports on website activity for website operators, and providing other
services relating to website activity and internet usage. Site usage data
collected through Google Analytics is not shared with other Google products
and tools. See Google's Privacy Policy and the Google Analytics Terms of
Service for further information.
                                                                              2

You can opt-out of making your site activity available to Google Analytics
through installation of the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.
Log Data
We collect informational data (“Log Data”) related to the transactions
performed by your computer and browser whenever you visit our Site.
This Log Data includes information such as your computer's Internet
Protocol ("IP") address, operating system and browser type and version, the
pages of our Site that you visit, any files downloaded, the time and date of
your visit, the time spent on those pages, any errors encountered and other
statistics.
This information is collected to assist in diagnosing any server problems,
site and security administration, identifying the most popular areas of the
site, and determining the sites effectiveness.
Voluntary or Personal Information
WCC is an institution of higher education and as such we must collect
certain “Information” about you, including Personal Identifiable Information
(and certain Sensitive Information, as defined in the European Union’s
General Data Protection Regulation), as a component of certain academic
and administrative processes and responsibilities. The College will only
collect personal information that you knowingly and voluntarily provide by,
for example, applying for admission, enrolling in College courses, seeking
employment at the College, or are alumni of the College. The information
collected, transmitted and process by the College is subject to WCC’s Data
Classification Policy.
HOW DO WE USE THIS INFORMATION?
WCC may use Information collected from students, prospective students,
alumni, faculty, staff and prospective employees to register and enroll
persons in the College, apply for employment, manage student and
employee accounts, manage financial aid, provide academic advising,
deliver education programs, analyze and improve education programs,
outreach, receive donations, make regulatory reports, comply with
accreditation requirements, and other related College processes and
functions. WCC may also use Information to conduct general demographic
                                                                           3

and statistical research to improve College programs. The College processes
such Information as necessary in the exercise of the College’s legitimate
interests, functions and responsibilities as a public higher education
institution.
WCC may share Information with third parties who have entered into
contracts with the College to perform functions on our behalf, subject to the
obligation of confidentiality and safeguards against unauthorized disclosure.
Generally, it is the College’s practice to use Information only for the
purposes for which it was collected. However, Information collected may be
subject to the College’s obligation to respond to subpoenas, court orders,
discovery requests and requests for public records under the Michigan
Freedom of Information Act.
WCC reserves the right to release any and all Information contained within
data logs concerning any visitor when they are deemed to be in violation of
the College’s Computing Resource Usage Policy or other published
guidelines, or engaged in any illegal or disruptive activity, even without a
subpoena, warrant, or other court order, and to release such information in
response to discovery requests, or in response to any circumstance in which
the College, in its sole discretion, deems an emergency. WCC cooperates
with law enforcement agencies in identifying those who may be using its
resources or services for illegal activities. WCC also reserves the right to
report any suspected illegal activity to law enforcement for investigation or
prosecution.
Personal Information you submit through our Site, such as your name,
address and other contact information, may be collected by the College for
internal marketing and development purposes as well as to respond to your
inquiry, complete a transaction for you, or fulfill other forms of customer
service. We will not share, sell, rent, swap or authorize any third party to
use your contact information for commercial purposes without your
permission.
WCC limits its own contact and solicitations to those users who have not
“opted out” of receiving such communications. The solicitations are limited
in that they, among other things, will clearly indicate the originator of the
email and provide the user with a method of “opting out” of receiving future
communications of a similar nature.
                                                                            4

HOW LONG DO WE STORE THE INFORMATION WE COLLECT?
WCC retains any personal information collected for at least the minimum
required retention according to applicable schedules located in the WCC
Record Retention Schedules or for at least the duration of your relationship
with College.
HOW DO WE STORE & PROTECT INFORMATION?
WCC uses appropriate technical and organizational security measures to
protect the confidentially, integrity and availability of your information
when you transmit it to the College. All information gathered on the Site is
stored within a controlled database accessible only to those authorized.
While this Site has reasonable security measures in place to help protect
against the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control,
no method of transmission over the Internet or method of electronic storage
is 100% secure.
Although the College has security measures in place to protect personal
information provided to us, users should also take steps to protect their
personal information and its disclosure. Information disclosed in email, chat
rooms, social media and other similar forums may become public. Users
should therefore exercise caution before disclosing personal information
when using these modes of communication. The College will never ask you
to provide personal information to us via an insecure method of
communication.
WCC complies with the Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard
(PCI-DSS). When you engage in financial transactions at our Site, you may
be asked for a credit card number. Unless otherwise noted, all credit card
transactions are encrypted and handled by an external credit card payment
gateway. The College does not retain credit card account number
information.
CHILDREN OR MINORS
This Site does not knowingly collect personal information from children or
minors under age 13 as defined by the Children’s Online Privacy Protection
Act (COPPA).
                                                                            5

“DO NOT TRACK” SUPPORT
"Do Not Track" (DNT) is a web browser setting that seeks to disable
tracking of an individual’s browsing activities. It is a proposed standard that
is under development. This Site does not currently respond to “Do Not
Track” settings.
RIGHTS FOR DATA SUBJECTS IN THE EUROPEAN UNION
To the extent applicable, the EU’s General Data Protection Regulation
(GDPR) grants data subjects in the EU the right, in certain circumstances, to
request access to, a copy of, rectification, restriction in the use of, or erasure
of your information. Your requests pursuant to the GDPR will be subject to
the retention periods of applicable U.S. federal and state law. The GDPR
provides further information about your rights. You also have the right to
lodge complaints with your national or regional data protection authority. If
you elect to exercise your rights under the GDPR, please contact WCC’s
Information Security Office at infosec@wccnet.edu or +1-734-477-8911.
REVISION HISTORY
 Version    Description         Revision Date        Review Date      Approver
   1.0      Initial version        10/11/18                 -             WJO
                                                                                 6
